Heavenly Tropical Cloud Cake features a vibrant compote of pineapple, mango, and passion fruit at its heart. It’s layered with velvety vanilla Chantilly cream atop a moist coconut sponge and encased in a light, airy marshmallow shell
Mix sugar and agar powder to prevent lumps when adding to liquid. Heat up water, passion fruit puree, add mango, pineapple
Mix sugar with agar-agar powder and whisk in the passion mixture, mix well and bring to boil and cook for 2 mins. Cool slightly
Transfer in the small half-ball silicone mold and freeze completely
Combine all dry ingredients, including dried shredded coconut, icing sugar, and flour, with 50g of egg whites
whisk the remaining egg whites with vinegar, and sugar until medium peaks form
Use ⅓ of the egg whites to mix into the flour mixture, then return it to the bowl with the egg whites. Fold them from top to bottom until fully incorporated
Transfer the batter to baking pan, run the skewer a few times to smooth the surface, tap a few times to release air bubbles, and bake at 350°F (180°C) for about 20 mins
Remove the cake from the oven and let it cool in the mold. Once cool, use cookie cutter cut into round shape which will fit your mold
Soak gelatin sheets in water for 10 mins to bloom. Discard water, microwave for 15 secs to melt, cool until liquid but not set
In a chilled mixing bowl, combine the heavy cream, mascarpone cheese, powdered sugar, and vanilla extract, whisk to soft peaks
With mixer on low, slowly pour melted gelatin into whipped cream. Increase speed, whip to stiff peaks. Don't overwhip
Transfer the stabilized Chantilly cream into a piping bag, pipe the cream into half-ball silicone molds
Place the frozen Pineapple-Mango-Passion Fruit Insert in the center, top with coconut sponge, cover with more cream, and freeze to set
Soak gelatin sheets in water for about 10 minutes to bloom, then discard the excess water. Microwave to melt
Mix egg whites with sugar. Hand whisk over simmering water until 113°F (45°C). Remove and whisk at high speed to soft peaks
Put water, sugar, and glucose into a pot. Cook till it reaches 230°F-235°F(110°C-113°C). Gradually pour the hot syrup into the egg whites mixture while whipping
After adding the syrup to the meringue, stir in the gelatin, and whip for another 30-40 seconds
Dip frozen cakes in marshmallow, then slowly lift to create a tip
Remove the skewer through the rack to release the cake without damaging the marshmallow shell
Cover the lower edges with fine shreaded coconut
Add gold leaf on the tip, then it's ready to serve
Subscribe for detailed recipes, clear instructions, and accessible ingredients to create elegant, artistic designs! ❤️❤️